You may ask yourself, what is data munching? Let's work
through an example and demonstrate the concept to you. Imagine
we're trying to figure out if right handed or left
handed baseball players have a higher batting average and we're
given this table of data to answer the question. Let's
look at the table. Look, this value is incorrect. You
can't have a batting average greater than 1,000. Also, it
looks like we don't have any left or right-handedness for
Ichiro Suzuki. Data wrangling is the art of dealing
with and or converting missing or ill-formatted data into
a format that more easily lends itself to analysis.
But before we can do that analysis, we first
have to get the data that we want to
analyze. Three of the most common sources from which
can get data are from files, from a database,
or from websites through web APIs. We'll cover all three
of these in this lesson.