Alright, why don't you try writing a quick sequel query
of your own on the India aadhaar data set. What we're
going to do is read in an aadhaar data CSV
to create a pandas data frame which can be queried using
sequel like syntax. We'll rename any columns that have spaces
in them with underscores and set all characters to lower case.
So if the columns names more closely resemble columns names
one might find in a table. Why don't you write query
that will select out the first 50 values
for registrar and enrollment agency in the aadhaar_data table.
Your queries should go here. So that's how we
pull all of the data out of SQL database.